JANANI SURESH KUMAR

+12269754716 | Kitchener, Ontario | jansuresh828@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | LeetCode

SUMMARY OF SKILLS

An Aspiring **Agile** Software Developer with **1+ years of working experience** in developing web and mobile applications using **React**, **JavaScript**. Proficient in **Java**, **Python** programming languages with excellent communication and teamwork skills developed through conducting tech events. Strong fundamental knowledge of **Data Structures**, **Algorithms**.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages Java, Python, JavaScript, React-native, React.js, TypeScript, HTML5, CSS
- Database SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Django, PostgreSQL
- Cloud Computing Kubernetes, GitHub actions, CI/CD, Docker, AWS
- Tools JIRA, GIT, Confluence, Android Studio, Xcode, Flutter, Eclipse, Zephyr Scale, Data dog, Sentry

EDUCATION

University of Windsor | Master of Applied Computer Science, Artificial Intelligence Stream Sep 2021 – Dec 2022 | CGPA: 90%

Rajalakshmi Engineering College | Bachelor of Computer Science Engineering

Aug 2017 – Apr 2021 | CGPA: 85.2% (First Class with distinction)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Prodigy Education | Full Stack Developer Intern

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022 | Ontario, Canada

Tech Stack: React-native, Typescript, Firebase, Agile, DevOps, GitHub Actions, CI/CD, Docker, Data Dog

- Automated production builds and CI/CD pipelines for iOS and android by maintaining consistency using GitHub
 actions and Fastlane scripts and reducing deployment time by up to 25%
- Developed Push notification feature for Prodigy mobile using Firebase RC across 50M+ users
- Collaborated with UI/UX team of 4 and designed react native user interface to promote using In-App Purchases

Takenmind Technologies Pvt Ltd | Software Engineer Intern

Sep 2020 - Dec 2020 | Chennai, India

Tech Stack: Reactjs, HTML5, CSS, Git, Jira, Sentry, BrowserStack, Figma

- Designed and Developed Login and Signup web page for TakenMind Technology Student Portal
- Constructed reusable React components with cross-browser compatibility of 95%. Integrated frontend and backend in compliance with customer requirements. Performed 50+ regression tests
- · Led weekly sprint planning meetings and estimated timeline for completion of tasks

PROJECTS

GOSQL (GitHub) | University of Windsor

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022 | Windsor, ON

Tech Stack: Java, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, SQL

- Built a database to access NoSQL data using SQL queries and implemented replication, db synchronization
- Converted 100,000 records of NoSQL data into 500,000 records of SQL data using PostgreSQL

Serwin Comm (GitHub) | University of Windsor

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021 | Windsor, ON

Tech Stack: REST APIs, Java, Firebase, Unity, AR

- Consolidated android mobile app offers 5 different services to serve the Windsor community
- Integrated augmented reality for consumers to test services before purchasing

Web Search Engine (GitHub) | University of Windsor

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021 | Windsor, ON

Tech Stack: Java, Jsoup, Hashing, Sorting, Trie Algorithm, Boyer Moore

- Created Java search engine that can handle up to 1,000 user requests and can process 100,000 URLs
- Built search engine with features Web crawler, pattern matching, Page ranking, HTML to text converter

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Build iOS, and Android Apps Udemy | Sep 2022
- MongoDB, Hadoop, Spark, Kubernetes LinkedIn Learning | Mar 2022
- Award for Best Poster representing 'Role of developers in Society' published at UWill Conference | Feb 2022
- Award for 'Jury's favorite product' in Techathon associated with IEEE | Sep 2019
- Linux training Certification IIT Bombay | May 2018